这是唯一一座在那些 管道上的建筑
It's the only building on top of those tunnels.
我们所要做的 就是进去
All we gotta do is get in there, on PI,
然后挖一个通道
and dig ourselves an on-ramp.
我一定会找出 你在那里干了什么
I'm gonna find out, you know,what it is you're doing up there.
如果要讨论谁有杀特伦斯的动机 我们需要一天的时间
If we talked about who had motive to kill Terrence,we'd be here all day.
-这和公司有什么关系  -算算看
-Anything to do with EcoField?  -Do the math.
一个公司的CEO因为诈骗而辞职 投资者开始损失
CEO gets indicted for fraud. Investors start losing money.
很多的钱
Lots of money.
你叫尼克·萨维恩 为终极正义做事
Call Nick Savrinn. Works for Project Justice.
他们在那?
They're here.
谁在那?
Who's here?
LJ? LJ?
你要过来接我
You gotta come get me.
我们不能 我们不在芝加哥 你过来找我们
We can't,we're not in Chicago. you have to come to us.
-月初到了 约翰  -是的 怎么了
-First of the month's coming up,John.  -Yeah. So?
看看我银行的帐户 看起来好象不足啊
I checked my balance on line. It's looking deficient.
明显的 菲波纳奇又出现了
Apparently Fibonacci's coming up for air again.
如果他在听证会上做证
If he testifies at that hearing
很多人都要遭殃 包括我
a lot of people are going down,including me.
听着 这个 呃
Listen. There, uh...
这里要权力变换
there's been a restructuring.
这是菲利决定的
This comes from Philly himself.
所以我现在是这里的管理了
So I'm the man in here now.
你他妈的在干什么
What the hell are you doin'? Aargh!
哦 我们有麻烦了
Uh-oh. We got a problem.
贝利克
Bellick?
这里发生什么了 那是做PI的人
What's going on? That's PI.
我负责的
I run it.
不在是了 你不再管了
Not any more, you don't.
贝利克
Bellick.
-嘿 老大  -小声点 犯人
-Hey, boss.  -Check that volume, inmate.
我们一起做事很久了 我们可以解决的对吧
We've been doing business too long. We can fix this thing,right?
让我说明白
Let's get something clear.
我们之间用不着胡扯 法尔曾是给我钱的人
You and I haven't done crap. Falzone's the one payin' me.
法尔曾就是一个信封
He's just an envelope.
你和我面对面的做这生意
You've been doing business with me face to face.
你想我被别人撒尿
You think I like getting piss thrown at me?
还是吐口水
Spit on?
这里别的笨蛋也许会为了 4万一年和那件小蓝制服这么做
Other chumps might do it for 40 grand a year and the little uniform,
但是我不会
but I'm not that dumb.
法尔曾的那信是我每天在 这的唯一原因
Falzone's envelope is the only reason I come through that fence every day.
也是我坚持每天在这里的唯一原因
And it's the only reason I'm gonna keep coming through that fence
直到我有足够的钱买下 湖边的房子
until I have enough money to buy a house on Lake Gray.
我想早点退休 约翰
I'm thinking early retirement, John.
可是你却在阻止我
And you're interfering with that.
嘿 老大 给我点时间
Hey, boss. Just give me some time
我可以给你法尔曾给你的 任何东西
and I can match whatever Falzone's paying you.
你出局了
You're out of business.
学着适应吧
Get used to it.
嘿 老大
Hey, boss.
老大
Boss!
他们就要找到它了
They're gonna find it.
只要他们在里面越长的时间
The longer they're in there,
他们就会越快的发现
the sooner they're gonna find it.
那我们就要回到那
Then we gotta get back in there.
我现在要告诉你一些疯狂的事
I'm gonna say something crazy to you now.
真是惊讶啊
Surprise, surprise.
我再也不管菲波纳奇了
I don't give a damn about that Fibonacci.
的确 这的确很疯狂
You're right. That is crazy.
因为我有更重要的事情要考虑 比如说活下去
Because I got bigger things to think about,like survival.
你知道 我在这里的朋友变少了
You see, I'm kinda short on friends in here,
除非你没有注意
in case you haven't noticed.
我要离开这里 现在
I need to get out, right now.
我还有我的生活
While I've still got my life.
那我们为什么说菲波纳奇
Then why are we talking about Fibonacci?
是这样 我弄回那间房子的 唯一办法
The only way I can get that room back
就是向 法尔曾证明我还有用
is if I can prove to Falzone I'm still worthy,that I've still got what it takes. Yeah?
那就是给他菲波纳奇 这样我们可以继续做我们的事情
And the only way I can do that is if I can give him Fibonacci.
有意思
Interesting.
你看 这不再是"你我对决"
You see, this is not a me-versus-you thing any more.
这是"我们"的事 对吧
This is us. An us thing, all right?
-是我们要逃出去  -是吗
-It's us for the escape.  -Is it?
或者是关于你回去和那些暴民一起的好处
Or is this about you getting back in good with the Mob again?
那种不再是我的生活了 嫩鸡
That life is over for me, fish.
我的意思是 他们折断了我的翅膀
I mean, they clipped my wings.
他们要我在这里腐烂
They want me to rot in here,
我和他们再也不是 联盟了
so I got no allegiance to them any more.
而你却还想帮他们
And yet you still want to do them a favour.
法尔曾绝望了
Falzone is desperate.
你看 如果菲波纳奇下个月 在法院作证
See, if Fibonacci testifies in front of the Congress next month,
法尔曾就完蛋了
Falzone's gonna go down in flames.
但是如果我们给他菲波纳奇
But if we give him Fibonacci,
他会给我们任何东西
he will give us anything.
任何东西 包括那一个特别房间
Anything. Including that very special room.
你怎么想 嫩鸡
What do you say, fish?
主对撒旦说
"And the Lord said unto Satan,
你愿意服从于我吗
'Hast thou considered my servant Job?"'
这世界上没有象他一样
"'That there is none like him in the earth.
是完美正直的人
A perfect and an upright man."'
一个敬畏上帝憎恶邪恶的人
"'One that fears God and shuns evil."'
-放弃他  -如果我这样 他们会杀了他
-Give him up.  -If I did,they'll kill him.
-也许这是他的报应  -就是这点 不是
-Maybe he deserves it.  -That's just it. He doesn't.
这个人是谁 你告诉我他是个黑手党
Who is this guy? You told me he was Mafia.
他为黑手党干 只是自己不知道
He was working for the Mafia.He just didn't know it.
奥托·菲波纳奇 是...
Otto Fibonacci is...
就象你一样
He's just like you.
一个无辜的人
An innocent man,
在错误的时间错误的地点被抓住
caught in the wrong place at the wrong time.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你知道的
You know
我没有偷你的东西 约翰
I didn't steal from you, John.
他是阿布鲁奇仓库的一个 中间管理者
He was management at one of Abruzzi's warehouses.
只是一个普通的人
Just a normal guy
工人阶级 教徒
working class, religious.
我没有偷你的东西 约翰
I didn't steal from you, John.
嘿 尼奇 尼奇 尼奇 尼奇
Hey, Nicky. Nicky, Nicky, Nicky.
嘘 嘘 嘘
Sh.Sh.Sh.
我是怎么告诉你说话要注意的
What did I tell you about talking?
约翰 求你了
John, please.
约翰 求你了 不
John, please. no
那人不会面对谋杀而置之不理
Somebody that couldn't turn his back on murder.
他发现阿布鲁奇和法尔曾 他一起工作的人
He realised that Abruzzi and Falzone,the men he worked for,
是杀人凶手
were killers.
他有他们所做一切的证据
He had the key to their dealings
可以让他们蹲一辈子监狱的东西
that could put them away for life.
现在他处于证人保护中
And now he's in witness protection for life.
法官问他为什么要站出来
The judge asked why he was coming forward with this information.
他说他认为这是正确的
He said it was because he thought it was the right thing to do.
现在什么是正确的迈克尔
What's the right thing to do now, Michael?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是如果我不放弃他
But if I don't give him up,
整件事就完了
this whole thing's over.
你告诉我的 如果
What you're telling me is if...
我要活着
if I'm to live...
一个好人就要死
A good man has to die.
凯勒曼
Kellerman
-你们已经在我们约定的地方了？  -是的
-You're where we discussed?  -Yes.
我还是不确定我们为什么在这
I'm still not exactly sure why we're here, but...
一个我的朋友一会儿来
A friend of mine should be along there shortly.
一个朋友？
A friend?
只是去了解你们的进展
Just to see where you are with things.
任何事都在控制当中
We're clear on where we are.Everything's under control.
没有什么会影响明天
Nothing is going to affect tomorrow,
-如果那是你所担心的  -我没有担心明天
-if you're worried.  -I'm not worried about tomorrow.
我的朋友是个解决问题的 就是这样
My friend is a problem solver, that's all.
如果你需要他他就为你效劳
He's there at your disposal if you need him.
帮我个忙
Do me a favour,
让他觉得自己是这个组的一部分 可以么
make him feel like part of the team, hm?
再联系
Talk soon.
-什么  -她带了某个人进来
-What?  -She's bringing someone in.
-这是什么意思  -她的口气变了
-What does that mean?  -Something in her tone changed.
你认为她知道那个小子么
You think she knows about the kid?
我们不知道
We don't know that.
我们不应该撒谎的
We shouldn't lie
-我们不应该告诉她我们抓住了那个小子  -难道不明白吗
-We shouldn't have told her we had the kid.  -What is it you don't understand?
我们如果告诉他那小子跑了 你我 我们现在就不在这了
We tell her that kid got away,you and I,we are not here now.
我对上帝发誓 这只会让我们越陷越深
I swear to God, it gets deeper and deeper.
这是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
如果我知道整件事到现在的地步
It means, if I'd have known how this was gonna turn out,
我决不会做联邦政府的垃圾活
I'd have got some crap job with the feds.
拿着笔 喝这咖啡 整天坐在办公桌边
Pushed pencils.Drank coffee all day long behind a desk.
上帝 听起来不错
God, that sounds good.
如果你还是这么说话 我会被迫杀了你
Keep talking like that,I'm gonna be forced to put a bullet in your head.
作为她的朋友
As for her friend,
不管怎么样
whoever that is,
我们找到他要的 我们装的很乖
we find out what he wants,we play nice,
我们看情况办事
we deal with it accordingly.
迈克尔 你最好来看看这个
Michael, you better see this.
嘿 杰西
Jersey!
把那个毛毯放到警卫室里么?
Are you putting that carpet in the guards' room?
是的 我想是的
Yeah, I think so.
什么时候?
When?
先把旧的撕碎
We gotta tear up the old stuff first.
然后我们就换
As soon as we're done with that.
可能是今晚或者明天
Tonight, tomorrow maybe.
兄弟 他们会发现的
They're gonna find it, bro.
他们会发现这个洞
They're gonna find the hole.
我们要做些什么
We gotta do something.
林肯
Linc.
吃饭
Chow.
这个是什么?
What's this?
这个嘛 你最后的晚餐
It's for, you know...your last meal.
写下你想要的东西
Write down what you want.
林肯 你要写些东西
Linc, you gotta write something down.
我什么也不想要
I ain't gotta do nothin'.
你不填
If you don't fill it out,
他们给你吃的是普通东西
all they're gonna give you is what's on chow for that day.
那又怎样?
So?
伙计 你不想最后一餐吃这个是吧
You don't want that for your last meal, man.
嗯?
Hm?
(东西放着了)万一你想起什么
In case you think of something.
嘿 戴眼罩的
Hey, Eyetie.
你那里需要什么?
Something you need there, rug head?
是啊 一份工作 伙计
Yeah, a job, man.
为什么你不把牢底打穿 我们不雇人
Why don't you hit the DQ down the street? We're not hiring.
我每个月 会给你一张百元大钞
I'll put a hundred in your kick every month.
你想给我钱来雇你?
You wanna pay me to work?
伙计我在厨房呆过8个月
I've been in the kitchen for eight months.
我擦过不只一个盘子
I scrub one more tray,
我准备去J-cat 你知道我说的是什么么?
I'm gonna go j-cat. you know what I say?
嘿 费列罗 怎么了?
Hey! Fiorello, how about it?
150.
那么算我一个
Sign me up, then, baby.
我正在想你所说的
I was thinking about what you said
这不是什么"你我对决"
that it's not a me-versus-you thing,
这是"我们"的事
it's an us thing.
对
That's right.
这件事上你准备走多远
How far are you willing to go with that?
我需要走多远就多远
As far as I have to.
那么和法尔曾约一下
Then set up a meeting with Falzone.
我想直接跟他谈谈
I wanna talk to him directly.
法尔曾不直接跟你这种人谈
Falzone doesn't talk to guys like you directly.
如果他想要菲波纳奇 他就会跟我谈的
If he wants Fibonacci, he's gonna have to.
不 不
No, no.
不 你听见我说的了
No, you heard me right
你说这个孩子 会放弃菲波纳奇?
This kid is gonna give up Fibonacci?
-你确定?  -当然 只是
-Sure?  -I'm definite. Only one thing,
他想直接和你见面
he wants to meet with you directly.
婊子养的 约翰 你做的对
Son of a bitch. You actually did something right. That's good.
好吧 我想我应该给那些 要打断你腿的人一个电话了
Guess I'll have to call off those guys I hired to shank you.
-开完笑的 约翰  -呵呵
-That was a joke, John.  -Funny.
好吧 我下午会去那里
Good. I'll come out there this afternoon.
约翰 听着
And, John,
如果我大老远的跑到那里
if I come all the way out there
而事实证明 这是浪费我的时间
and this turns out to be a waste of my time,
我要阉了你
I'm gonna castrate you.
我希望你理解
I hope you understand that.
保重 兄弟
Be well, my friend.
我也爱你
I love you too.
他一会过来
He's coming.
别搞砸了
Don't mess this up.
你好
Hello
是我
It's me.
我知道
I know.
我看见"狱友"的号码
I saw "Inmate" on the caller ID.
记得我说过 要你给菲波纳奇打电话?
Remember when I said I might be calling you on Fibonacci?
记得
Yes.
好吧 现在是时候了
Well... it's time.
你看起来心神不宁
You seem distracted.
我猜 很多东西在我脑子里
Got a lot on my mind, I guess.
是么?
Yeah?
与那些拿了这些脚趾的人有关么?
Have anything to do with the people who took these toes?
-花很漂亮  -是的
-Nice flowers.  -Right.
我们有崇拜者么?
Do we have an admirer?
我父亲给的
They're from my father.
哦 为什么送的?
Ah. What's the occasion?
-我的生日  -今天?
-It's my birthday.  -Today?
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧
OK.
没什么
Nothing.
生日通常不是什么痛苦的话题 是吧
Birthday's aren't usually a sore subject, that's all.
除非庆祝者想到她的年龄
Unless the celebrant is feeling her age,
这一点我在你身上看不出
which I don't see how you could be.
迈克尔 我29岁了 我没有觉得自己变老
I'm 29 years old, Michael. I'm not feeling my age.
不过是29个生日罢了
It's just, out of those 29 birthdays,
我的爸爸实际上就和我呆了6个生日
my father has actually managed to see me on precisely six of them.
因此 取而代之就给我买了一些花
So, I get flowers instead.
花儿最后都会枯死的 一个礼拜后 就会被丢到垃圾桶里
Flowers that end up dead and in the trash a week later.
听起来很伤感 是么?
That sounded bitter, huh?
有点
Kind of.
没什么大不了的
It's not a big deal.
好了 明天见
You are all set. I will see you tomorrow.
好吧
OK.
我很抱歉你那么想
I'm sorry you feel that way.
我是说 花儿的事
About the flowers, I mean.
嘿 过来个人
Hey,someone's get on here
-我想把这些放到其他房间  -我来干老板
-I want these in the other room.  -I got it, boss.
躲开 小白脸 我干了
Hey, chill-lily white. I got it.
来吧 我知道你在附近
Come on,I know you're around here somewhere.
他看上去不怎么好?
He's not doing well, is he?
他的妈妈刚去世
He just lost his mother.
10天后他会失去他的父亲
Ten days from now, he loses his father.
你怎么样?
How are you holding up?
你知道 我
You know, I...
我有点明白你最近的心情 LJ
I sort of get what you're going through here, LJ.
没有冒犯的意思 我不认为你能理解
No disrespect, but I don't know that you do.
我理解你,我爸爸也有同样遭遇
No, with my dad,
我像你这么大的时候 也跟你同样的处境
I was in the same spot when I was your age.
他进了监狱
He was in prison,
就像你爸爸一样 他也是清白的
and my dear daddy was innocent.
怎么了?
What happened?
我是说 最后
I mean, you know, at the end.
就像我现在希望发生的
What I hope happens here
他后来被证明无罪
he got exonerated.
他们说他干了什么?
What did they say he did?
一大堆的坏事
A lot of bad things.
都不是真的
They weren't true,
我们证明了这点
and we proved that.
每一天 每一天都要面临失败...
Every day. Every day was a lost cause,
但我们还是要一直斗争
but we kept fighting.
我是说,不然还能去干什么?
I mean, what else are you gonna do
如果你爱一个人 你会任由他落得那样的下场吗?
when you love somebody? Let them go out like that?
所以你要斗争
So you fight.
一直斗争
You keep fighting.
决不放弃
You never give up.
我们会成功的
We're gonna beat this thing.
对不对?
OK?
-你好  -你好
-Hello.  -Hello.
你在等我拜访
You were expecting me?
-一个我们共同的朋友安排的...  -是的
-A mutual friend arranged it.  -Yes.
-我能不能...  -请吧
-You mind if I...?  -Please.
嘿 你好...
Hey, how are...
-不好意思 我还不知道你叫什么  -奎因
-I'm sorry, I didn't get your name.  -Quinn.
奎因先生 你能告诉我你是来干什么的吗?
Mr Quinn, mind telling us what we're doing here?
你看我的样子应该能看出来了
You can probably tell just by looking at me,
我不是那种惹事生非的人
I'm not a wave-making sort.
你就把我当作一个监督员好了
Just think of me as a supervisor
来确保所有事情都顺利 因为...
who's here to make sure things are under control as we approach...
那个 大事情要来了
you know,the big event.
我倒觉得事情都挺顺利的
I wasn't aware that things were out of control.
你最清楚不过了 不是吗?
Well, you'd be the one that would know,wouldn't you?
其实 我来这里的原因是 你们所知道的事情
Well, the reason I'm here is because there's a discrepancy between what you know
和你们告诉副总统的并不相符
and what you have said to the vice president.
你们想要解决掉的律师 他们现在还安然无恙
The lawyers you tried to blow up are still running around
还是活蹦乱跳的 你们知道 我也知道
healthy as thoroughbreds.You know it,I know it.
那个小孩也一样
Same thing goes with the kid,
你们真是愚蠢至极 居然告诉副总统你们已经把小孩捉到了
who you were silly enough to tell the old lady that you were actually in possession of.
我要说的事情可以归结为
Everything that I'm saying is boiling down to this.
你们现在得把控制权转交我
You gotta hand the reins over to me now,
这样我才能帮你们
so that I can save your ass.
首先...
First of all...
不!
No! No.
瞧? 现在是你逼我动手
See, now you made me make a wave.
你跟你的搭档现在被停职 什么时候复职另行通知
You and your partner are off the job until further notice.
这不是我的命令 也不是白宫的命令
It doesn't come from me,it doesn't come from the White House
是公司的命令 明白了吗?
it comes from the company. You understand?
你的指骨断了两根
Your proximal and middle phalanx are broken.
用冰敷45分钟 然后用夹板固定
just ice it for 45 minutes then splint it.
医生会这样跟你说
That's what a doctor would tell you to do,
所以你现在没必要再去找医生了
so you don't need to go see one.
易科菲尔德公司的SEC档案?
EcoField's SEC files.
特伦斯·斯蒂德曼被杀了
Terrence Steadman was murdered
那么控告他的诉讼文件就应该被公开 对不对?
so information from his indictment wouldn't be public,right?
当然是 但是到现在还没有被公开
Sure,but we have no way of knowing
我们不可能知道他们到底想掩盖什么
what they were trying to cover up.
斯蒂德曼的妻子说如果他丈夫垮了 公司会损失上亿美元
Steadman's wife said there're hundreds of millions of dollars at stake if her husband went down
所以我想沿着钱的线索去找 看看会找到什么
So I figure we follow the money and see where it takes us.
1.09亿美元
109 million,
2.12亿美元...
212 million.
我目前为止发现
Over half a billion dollars I've found so far
超过5亿美元的联邦政府拨款 用于易科菲尔德公司的代用燃料研发
in federal grants to EcoField for alternative fuel research.
真是好大一笔钱
That is a hell of a lot money.
但用来干什么了?
But for what?
不仅仅说公司没创造利润
Not only did the company never make a profit,
据我所知,他们没做出任何东西
as far as I can tell, they never made anything.
没有燃料电池 没有专利 没有新发现 什么都没有
No fuel sales, no patents,no findings, nothing.
那么易科菲尔德公司是假的 只是个掩饰?
So EcoField was a sham. It was a cover.
问题在于 为了什么?
The question is, for what?
菲利
Philly.
坐下,孩子
Sit down, kid.
那么... 菲波纳奇
So... Fibonacci
-怎么能找到他?  -做做功课
-how'd you find him?  -I did my homework.
你再跟我打哈哈
You get elliptical with me for one more second
我就取消交易
and I will cancel you.
明白吗?
You understand me?
配合一点 嫩鸡
Give it up, fish.
在证人被转交给 美国马歇尔部门保护之前
Before someone's transferred to the marshals and placed in protection,
他们在审判所在地由警长看管
they're guarded by a local sheriff from the county where the trial will take place.
请接索罗曼警长
Sheriff Solomon, please.
请稍等
Please hold.
我是安德鲁·索罗曼
Andrew Solomon here.
既然这个警长能接电话
If the sheriff was available,
那肯定不是看管菲波纳奇的那个
he wasn't the one guarding Fibonacci.
普特南郡警长办公室
Putnam County Sheriff's Office.
呃 普罗泽警长在吗?
Yeah, is Sheriff Pronzo there?
对不起 普罗泽警长去度假了
I'm sorry. Sheriff Pronzo's on vacation.
-真的?  -是的,先生
-Really?  -Yes, sir.
整个郡只有4个警长
There are only four sheriffs in the county.
因为普罗泽是唯一不在自己办公室的
Since Pronzo was the only one not in his office,
而且他妻子和孩子都没跟他一起去度假
and his wife and kids were at home,
所以我知道他肯定 是在跟菲波纳奇一起度假
I knew the only vacation he was taking was with Fibonacci.
看守他直到转交保护
Watching him till they could put him in protection.
问题是 有时狱警部门 要花好几个星期才能建立新ID
Thing is, sometimes it takes weeks for the marshals service to set up a new identity,
所有某地方警长就跟菲波纳奇 呆在什么偏僻的地方
so some local sheriff is stuck in the middle of nowhere with Fibonacci.
他觉得孤独 然后不断的打电话回家
He gets lonely and calls home,a lot.
我打电话到通信公司 说我是普罗泽 我把账单弄丢了
I called the phone company,said I was Pronzo and I'd lost my bill.
我要求多要一份
I asked for another copy.
发现普罗泽先生接过很多次的电话 都是从一个远离芝加哥的地方
Mrs Pronzo was receiving dozens of calls from an area code a long way from Chicago.
我上网去 反查这个电话号码 然后
I went online,reverse-traced the number, and voila
就发现了菲波纳奇所在的地址
There was Fibonacci's exact location.
-你怎么知道他还在那?  -我叫人跟踪他...
-How do you know he's still there?  -I have someone looking after him.
远远地监视 怕他搬走了
Watching from afar, in case he moves.
你是想要钱 是不是?
This is about money, isn't it?
-你真是善解人意 法尔曾先生  -什么?
-You're an astute man.  -What?
约翰 你的朋友想敲诈我
Your friend here John,is trying to extort me.
不是敲诈 是保险费
Not extortion, insurance.
我打算有一天要逃出这里
I plan on being out of here one day.
我不希望到时 我的简历在大部分地方被拒绝
I don't think my new resume is gonna cut it in most places.
-你要多少?  -20万美元
-How much?  -200,000.
-我要杀了你  -等价物
-I'm gonna kill you.  -Quid pro quo.
我们各得所需
You scratch my back, I scratch yours.
好吧 我给你些等价物
Well, I'll give you some quid pro quo.
你从哪弄来的?
Where did you get this?
这张照片是谁拍的?
Who took this picture?
既然你能让人在外面监视我们感兴趣的人
Since you took it upon yourself to have some people watch our interests on the outside,
我们也能让人监视你感兴趣的人
we took it upon ourselves to have some people watching yours.
那么你要哪个?
So who's it gonna be?
菲波纳奇还是你这个漂亮的女朋友?
Fibonacci or your pretty little girlfriend there?
嘿 看看你在跟谁说话 嫩鸡
Yeah, you should be careful with who visits you in here, fish.
不要乱说话
These walls have eyes.
如果你敢碰她 我会亲手杀了你
If you touch her,I'll kill you myself.
第一 这是一个无力的威胁
One, that is an empty threat.
你对我来说连个虫子都不如
You are less than a gnat to me.
第二 把地址给我
And two,all you gotta do is give me the address
我们将各自避免一场闹剧
and we avoid all this melodrama altogether.
给我地址 你这只虫子
The address, you gnat.
就现在!
Now.
答应我
Promise me...
答应我下手快点 不要让他太痛苦
promise me it'll be quick and painless.
-这家伙脑子有问题吧？   -答应我
-Do you believe this guy?  -Promise me.
如果接下来从你嘴里吐出来的不是地址
If the next thing that comes out of your mouth is not that address,
很多人...都会受到伤害的
there's gonna be a lot of pain...in a lot of places.
加拿大
Canada.
哈曼尔顿大街345号
345 Hamilton Avenue,
安大略湖桑德湾
Thunder Bay, Ontario.
你可以滚了
Get outta here.
做得很好 约翰
Nice work, John.
我想把我们的约翰·阿布鲁奇 处死未免太夸张了
I guess the demise of John Abruzzi was greatly exaggerated.
多谢 我很感激
Thank you. I appreciate it.
你能不能帮我把贝利克的事摆平?
Could you do me a favour and fix this Bellick thing for me?
没问题
Yeah, consider it done.
多谢
Thank you.
菲利 在你开枪前
And Philly.Before you pull the trigger,
看着那杂种的眼睛 替我向他道别
look that son of a bitch in his eyes and tell him John Abruzzi said goodbye.
"在通往世界和平和繁荣的竞争中 美国将始终处于领先"
"In the race toward worldwide peace and prosperity,America will set the pace."
"竞争"?
"Race"?
你死我活 武力竞争
Rat race, arms race...
你能想出一个更槽的词吗?
Can you think of a word with a worse connotation?
搞定它
Fix it.
-你帮我请了个保姆?  -现在谈这个不是时候
-Did you send me a baby-sitter?  -This is not the time or the place.
-现在不是时候 什么时候才是？  -别用那种口气跟我说话
-This is the time and the place.  -Don't take that tone with me.
看看你在和谁说话
Remember who you are talking to.
我是这个国家的副总统
I am vice president of this country.
不 事实上 你是来自伊利诺伊 蒙加马利的卡罗琳·雷纳德
No, actually you're Caroline Reynolds from Montgomery, Illinois.
我知道你是谁
I know exactly who you are.
跟我来
Come with me.
有些事情你必须清楚...
There is something you need to understand.
如果你完成了你的工作...
If you had done yourjob,
我也不会让奎因来帮忙
I never would've had to ask for Quinn.
你也要弄明白一些事情
And there's something you need to understand.
你把这些家伙招来 就等于唤醒了一头野兽
You woke a sleeping beast when you called these guys in.
他们的手段多得很...
They have a bigger agenda than any of us
他们会用尽一切办法达到目的
and get real nasty real quick if things don't go their way.
到那时 没人是安全的了
So now no one is safe
你不是
not you,
我也不是
not me.
不要反应过度
Let's not overreact.
我的意思是 每个人都对将来感到恐惧
I mean, I know everyone is nervous about tomorrow.
我了解
I understand that.
但我们都要记得的一件事是...
But the one thing both of us have to remember
我们是一条船上的 对吗?
is that we are in this together, OK?
我所要说的是现在 这些家伙介入到这件事里了
All I'm saying is these guys are into this thing now,
这已经无法挽回了
and there's no going back.
对任何人 这都是一个坏消息
That's bad news for everyone.
塞巴斯蒂安·贝尔夫?
Sebastian Balfour?
-是的 怎么?  -我是 内斯特·帕艾克.
-Yeah.   -Yeah, I'm Nestor Pollack.
中西部人寿保险公司
Midwestern Life and Casualty.
我已经参保其他公司了
I'm already covered.
多谢
Thanks.
哦不 我来这想了解一下 维罗妮卡·多诺万的情况
oh no, I'm here to discuss Veronica Donovan.
她怎么了?
What about her?
恩 我们试过联系她...
We've been trying to track her down
因为公寓爆炸的财产损失...
with respect to the propety damage from the apartment explosion.
-爆炸?  -你不知道?
-Explosion?  -You didn't know.
哦 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
她的记录上说你是他的未婚夫...
It's just that her records,they list you as her fiance,
-所以 我想...  -等等
-so I assumed...  -Hold on.
-维罗妮卡现在还好吗?  -恩 有些不幸发生
-Is Veronica OK?  -Well, there has been a fatality.
别误会 事实上法医说死者的身份
But the medical examiners haven't been able to identify the remains
还有待确认
with any certainty,
所以维罗妮卡应该没事 我们只是找不到她
so Veronica could be OK, we just can't find her.
我们希望你能提供一些帮助
We were hoping you could help.
我是LJ 和维罗妮卡在一起 我很好 我爱你
我爱你
罗兹
Rozz.
李斯
Reese.
不伦斯
Burrows.
蓝莓薄煎饼?
Blueberry pancakes, huh?
很好 伙计 我给你去弄
All right, man. You got it.
蓝莓薄煎饼
Blueberry pancakes.
维罗妮卡 你从那逃出来了吗? 我很担心你
我没事
谢天谢地 你在哪?
不能说 我得下了 再见
四十一
Fourty-one.
四十五
Fourty-five.
就是这里了
This is it.
好了 孩子们 该睡觉了
All right, that's it, kids. Time for bed.
亲一下
Give me a kiss.
下面那个还好吧?
Are you OK down there?
晚安
Night-night.
好了 亲爱的 亲一个
All right, sweetheart. Give me a kiss.
孩子们都睡下了
The kids are down.
多谢
Thanks.
今晚 我们是来送信的 先生们
Tonight we send a message, gentlemen.
我们要让他看看伤害家人是什么感受
We are gonna hurt him and his family the way he hurt ours.
-哦 亲爱的?  -恩
-Oh, honey.  -Yeah?
你出去的时候顺便调一下 洒水器的定时开关好吗?
Can you change the timer on the sprinkler when you out there?
好的
OK.
-爱你   -我也爱你
-Love you.  -Love you too.
不许动 放下枪!
Freeze!
警察! 放下武器!
Police! Drop your weapons!
我说了放下枪!
Drop it!
趴下!
Down!
堪萨斯托皮卡论坛报
喂 我是约翰
Hi, it's John.
你找我有事?
You wanted to talk to me?
是的 你看到新闻了吗
Yeah. You hear the news?
法尔曾昨晚在加拿大被抓了
Falzone got popped last night, up in Canada.
非法持枪过境
International gun charges,
无权保释
parole violation...
他麻烦大了
He's in deep.
你把花都扔了
You threw away your flowers.
是的就象我说的那样 它们不能长久
Like I said, they don't last.
我想它们还没枯呢
I don't think they're dead yet.
我不喜欢接触不能长久的东西
I don't like getting attached to things if I know they won't last.
按住
There you go.
你为什么这样世故
Why are you so cynical?
我想都和世故 还有现实有关
I think there's cynicism and there's realism.
但还有乐观主义
And there's optimism.
希望 信念
Hope, faith.
从一个关在牢里8个脚趾囚犯口中说出来?
Coming from an eight-toed guy locked in a penitentiary?
已经没那么多了脚趾了
Toes are overrated.
谢谢你逗我开心
Thank you for trying to make me smile.
今天没心情
Not today.
不一定噢
You never know.
好了
We're all set.
我们有很多要谈 嫩鸡
You and I have a lot to talk about,don't we, fish?
似乎法尔曾在加拿大遇上麻烦了啊
Seems Philly Falzone ran into some problem up in Canada
都是因为你给的消息
just because of the information you gave him.
什么麻烦
What kind of trouble?
非法持枪过境 无权保释
International gun charges, parole violation.
他要消失一阵子了
He's gonna go away for a long time.
你觉得怎么样呢?
How do you feel about that?
真他妈太好了
Pretty darn good.
-PI怎么办?  -我又负责了
-And what about PI?  -We got that back too.
法尔曾昨天把钱给比利了 现在暂时处境不错
Falzone paid Bellick yesterday, so we're good. For now.
-问题都解决了?   -当然
-It all worked out.  -Sure did.
干的好
Nicely done.
你真会演戏
You're a hell of an actor.
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
这个派上用场了
This helped.
不错
It's nice.
拍的不错
Nice shot.
从哪找来的
Where did you take it?
林肯的 白天要的
It's Lincoln's from back in the day.
露营时照的
A camping trip or something.
那么我们什么时候回去开工
So when do we get back in that room?
-马上  -好 那就准备开始吧
-Right away.  -Well,let's get to it.
对了 还有件事
Oh, just one more thing.
我们出去后你会把菲波纳奇交给我 对吧？
You are gonna give me Fibonacci once we're outside these walls, right?
当然
Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
我看我还是要把它留下
And I think I'll keep this,
以防万一
as insurance.
还要果汁吗?
Juice?
为什么我们每天都要吃早饭
Why we have breakfast every day?
你必须每天都吃 LJ
You should have breakfast every day, LJ.
早餐很重要
It's an important meal.
我是说为什么我们不能 每天在一起吃早饭
No, why can't I have breakfast with you every day?
这样已经很不错了
Nothing would make me happier.
但你妈妈和我
But your mommy and me,
我们不住在一起了
we don't live together any more.
为什么
Why?
有时爸爸妈妈之间会就是这样的
Well, uh...sometimes that happens with mommies and daddies.
知道吗?
But you know what?
你是世界上最幸运的孩子了
You're the luckiest boy in the world,
因为你妈妈很爱你
because your mommy loves you very much
我也很爱你
and I love you very much.
每个星期天...
I tell you what, how about every Sunday
我们俩都可以一起 吃最特别的早餐
we have our own special breakfast?
就你和我 怎么样?
Just you and me.
-好吗?  -好
-Yeah?  -Yeah.
-要一点还是一把(蓝莓)  -一把
-Little bit or a handful?  -Handful.
一把
Handful.
开始做了
Here we go.
闪一边去
Take a walk.
谁想和他一起走?
Anyone else want to walk with him?
好的
Yeah.
这里我说了算
This is my game.
看来我们的朋友又恢复地位了啊
Looks like our friend got his throne back.
好象是的
Looks like it.
我感觉这和你有关
Something tells me we may have you to thank for that.
-你不会想知道的  -说对了
-You don't want to know.  -you gotta damn right.
走开 老头
Stretch your legs, old head.
看来我们之间有很多事要谈 是吧
Now,we got a hell of a lot to talk about, don't we?
没什么好谈的
I got nothing to say.
你以为你能耍我 白小子?
You think you can play me, snowflake?
因为你上过几年学?
Cos you got college?
有学问了?
Big-school learning, huh?
让我来教你
Well, let me school you.
在这围墙里达尔文说了算(优胜劣汰)
Darwin wins inside these walls.
不是爱因斯坦 是达尔文
Not Einstein, Darwin.
放风时间结束了 小子们
Yard time's over, ladies.
集合
Let's line it up.
我们之间还没完呢
I'm not done with you, fish.
你连开始的机会都没有
You never even got started.
好了
All right.
我们已经打通最硬的部分了
We're through the hard part.
再来18英寸,我们就挖到管道了
Another 18 inches, we'll hit that pipe.
我们星期五就能挖到
We'll be there by Friday.
星期五?
Friday?
最好开始准备旅行了
Better start making travel arrangements.
玛丽克鲁兹 我要来了 宝贝
Maricruz,here I come,baby
撒丁岛 我来了
Sardinia,here I come
我们去哪里?
Where are we going?
-巴拿马  -巴拿马
-Panama.  -Panama.
巴拿马
Panama.
达里安 运河南部
Darien Gap, south of the canal.
没有公路 电力
No roads, no electricity,
没有警察
no cops.
只有白色的沙滩和冰冻的啤酒
Nothing but white sand beaches and ice-cold beer.
这很不错 但我们的余生会怎样?
Well,that's nice, but what about our lives?
我不知道
I don't know
-或者开潜水用品店  -我不会潜水
-Well, we'll open a scuba shop.  -Hey, I don't dive.
我也不会 但我们有很多时间去学
Neither do I. We'll have plenty of time to learn.
老大来了
Bulls.
这家伙说他也在这里干活
This con says he's on a job in here.
-我想不是这么回事  -听到了吧
-I don't think so.  -You heard the paisano.
-给我出去  -长官 等一等
-Move your ass.  -CO,hold on one second.
你肯定没搞错?
Now, are you sure about that?
你确定不需要人帮忙?
Are you sure you can't use an extra hand?
你对结构的东西懂多少?
You know anything about construction?
混凝土结构是我的专长
Concrete is my specialty.
你懂吗?
Can you dig it?
好吧 长官
OK, boss.
-我要他  -随便你
-Sign him up.  -You got it.
这果然是一个弱肉强食的世界 对吗 嫩鸡?
Now it looks like Darwin wins after all, eh, fish?
有太多疑点 没法联系在一起
I have a lot of dots,but no way to connect them.
这里没人因此暴富
Nobody's getting rich here.
那些股东们呢
What about shareholders?
好处不多 最终都要 纳入董事会的支配之下
Profits were all converted back to shares.
似乎他们把一些 研究和发展项目转包了出去
Looks like they subcontracted out some researches and development
但这些只是蝇头小利
but it's pennies in the scheme of things.
没人提早退休
Nobody got early retirement.
你不能移几个小数点 就让5亿元消声匿迹
But you can't hide $500 million by moving a few decimal points.
就像学者预期的那样
In a move anticipated by many pundit,
副总统雷纳德 日前宣布将会角逐总统选举
The Vice President Reynolds announced she is running for the presidency.
在家乡伊利诺斯州蒙哥马利的演讲上 她作出如下声明
She made the announcement from her hometown of Montgomery.
迈向世界和平和经济繁荣的步伐 注定是长期的 不可一蹴而就
The move toward worldwide peace and prosperity is a marathon,not a sprint,
但我保证美国将会领导世界的发展
but I assure you,America will be setting the pace.
5亿美元的用处可大着呢 支撑一个小国都绰绰有余了
$0.5 billion doesn't disappear.You could run a small country with that.
据报道 副总统背后有 有史以来最大的竞选资本支持
The vice president is reported to have the largest campaign war chest in history.
因为竞选金额巨大 她被视为
It's so large,in fact,the prognosticators are already
她被视为 最有可能当选的总统候选人
casting her as the favorite in the presidential race.
也许不是用在小国身上
Maybe not a small country.
是最大的这个
Maybe this one.